



Herndon, VA 20170



507-213-4872



abdizm@outlook.com

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Commerce

Accounting Osmania University, Hyderabade , India April 2010

Bootcamp

Web Development CareerFoundry, Berlin

ZAKARIA ABDI

SUMMARY

User-minded Web Developer with a background in mental health. Able to translate skills in teaching and implementing evidence-based practices to effectively communicate with clients and create purposeful web solutions. Driven to grow expertise in website development by utilizing an analytical mindset and creativity to design responsive apps from start to finish.

SKILLS

- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS
- Web and Application Servers
- Javascript Libraries and Frameworks
- Azure Deployment
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- · Data Modeling

EXPERIENCE

DIRECT SUPPORT PROFESSIONAL

Albryte Support Services | Sterling, VA | December 2020 - Current

- Assisted with building life and social skills useful for everyday activities and interactions.
- Planned and implemented individualized interventions as part of behavior treatment plans.
- Understood autism spectrum disorder, associated behaviors and optimum treatments.

NURSE AIDE

Home Instead Senior Care | Manassas, VA | November 2020 - February 2021

- Assisted patients with shaving, bathing and oral hygiene to promote healthy habits and overall wellness.
- Collected and documented vital signs to track current patient conditions.

RIDESHARE DRIVER

Uber And Lyft | Baltimore, MD | June 2019 - November 2020

- Achieved consistently high customer scores due to exceptional service.
- Cleaned vehicle regularly to maintain professional appearance.

PRODUCTION OPERATOR

HS Bakery | Baltimore, MD | March 2017 - May 2019

• Examined final products for conformance with quality and design

standards.

 Recommended process improvements to enhance operational safety and efficiency.

SALES ASSOCIATE

7 Eleven Store | Baltimore, MD | January 2016 - January 2017

- Assisted teammates with sales-processing tasks to meet daily sales goals.
- Built trusting relationships with customers by making personal connections.

SHIPPING AND RECEIVING ASSOCIATE

US Embassy Djibouti | Djibouti, Republic Of Djibouti | September 2012 - January 2015

- Produced daily reports on shipments, team performance and financial numbers.
- Checked customer orders, labeling and documentation prior to shipment to avoid delays.

CARGO SUPERVISOR

DHL Global Forwarding | Djibouti, Republic Of Djibouti | February 2011 - September 2012

- Produced bills of lading and updated shipment status information.
- Adhered to airline cargo policies, monitored operations and reported discrepancies to management for review.

LANGUAGES

English:	French:
Full Professional	Full Professional
Arabic:	
Professional	